<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Module4</string>
    <string name="nsg_mission">The National Security Guard (NSG) is an Indian special forces unit under the Ministry of Home Affairs (MHA). It was raised in 1984, following Operation Blue Star and the assassination of Indira Gandhi (for combating terrorist activities with a view to protect states against internal disturbances).
        \n\nNSG is under the authority of Ministry of Home Affairs. However it is not categorised under the uniform nomenclature of Central Armed Police Forces. It has a special forces mandate, and its core operational capability is provided by the Special Action Group (SAG) which is drawn from the Indian Army. The Special Rangers Group (SRG), the police component of NSG, which also handles VIP security, is composed of personnel on deputation from other Central Armed Police Forces and State Police Forces.
\n\nThe NSG personnel are often referred to in the media as Black Cats because of the black outfit and black cat insignia worn on their uniform.
\n\nThe National Security Guard (NSG) was set up in 1984 as a Federal Contingency Deployment Force to tackle all facets of terrorism in the country. As a specialized counter terrorism force, it is intended for use (only in exceptional situations) and not meant to take over the (functions of the State Police Forces or other Para Military Forces). Yet, over the years its role has vastly expanded to provide personal security to influential politicians quite independent of the real threat that they face.
\n\nThe NSG is trained to conduct counter terrorist task to including counter hijacking tasks on land, sea, and air; Bomb disposal (search, detection and neutralization of IEDs); PBI (Post Blast Investigation) and Hostage Rescue missions.
    </string>
    <string name="nsg_sel">Selection is demanding and has a drop out rate of about 70–80 percent. Three of their 14 months of training in Manesar, Haryana, are devoted to the basics.The basic training period lasts 90 days. Physical fitness training has 26 elements, ranging from a cross-country obstacle course to jumping from heights and across divides and scaling different kinds terrain. One endurance test involves martial arts, target shooting at the end of an obstacle-ridden cross-country run. This is meant to gauge the candidate’s performance under conditions of stress and exhaustion. Those who successfully complete the tests are sent for nine months of advanced training.</string>
    <string name="nsg_reg_dep">In response to criticism of the time taken by NSG units to arrive in November 2008 Mumbai attacks, from their base in Manesar, Haryana, the MHA decided to deploy NSG contingents in major cities across India like Mumbai, Kolkata (462 personnel), Hyderabad and Chennai.
    \n\nHyderabad will also serve as a regional center in the future. With the ministry of home affairs (MHA) giving its nod and sanctioning Rs 533.68 crore a few months ago, the National Security Guard (NSG) officials are gearing up to set up the Southern Regional Center (SRC) at Ibrahimpatnam, Hyderabad for training commandos. With the state government also handing over 600 acres at Ibrahimpatnam, the SRC is likely to be ready by next year. Tender notices have already been issued for civil works, which would be overseen by the Central Public Works Department. With this, Hyderabad would have an NSG hub at Trimulgherry as well as the SRC for training "Black Cats". As of now, nearly 300 commandos, ready for anti-terror operations round-the-clock, are stationed at the NSG hub at Trimulgherry. Similar hubs are in place in Mumbai, Chennai and Kolkata. The proposal to set up a state-of-the-art NSG training centre at Ibrahimpatnam on the lines of NSG Manesar training centre has been pending for over three years.
        \n\nBut the MHA officials, in their annual report released recently, announced the release of funds for developing infrastructure. "Post the 26/11 Mumbai terror strike, four regional hubs of NSG were operationalised in Mumbai, Hyderabad, Chennai and Kolkata to reduce reaction time. A regional centre at Hyderabad is also being raised, for which 600 acres of land has been acquired. MHA has conveyed sanction of Rs 533.68 crore towards the construction of this Southern Regional Centre, NSG at Ibrahimpatnam," the MHA report said. With this, the state would have two trained anti-terror striking forces. Besides the NSG, the Andhra Pradesh police's OCTOPUS, which also has a training facility at Ibrahimpatnam, has a strength of over 250 personnel. NSG and OCTOPUS personnel, who undergo a gruelling training, including handling sophisticated weapons, commandos are sent back to their parent department once they attain the age of 35, ensuring that the force remains young and fighting fit.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_bsfmission">Border Security Force</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        Till 1965 India’s borders with Pakistan were manned by the
        State Armed Police Battalion. Pakistan attacked Sardar Post,
        Chhar Bet and Beria Bet on 9 April, 1965 in Kutch. This exposed
        the inadequacy of the State Armed Police to cope with armed
        aggression due to which the Government of India felt the
        need for a specialized centrally controlled Border Security
        Force, which would be armed and trained to man the International
        Border with Pakistan. As a result of the recommendations of the
        Committee of Secretaries, the Border Security Force came into
        existence on 01 Dec 1965, and Shri K F Rustamji was the first
        chief and founding father. Shri K K Sharma, IPS is current Director
        General of the BSF.\n\n\n

        The BSF, in its 53rd years of existence, has emerged as an elite force of the country having excelled with distinction in the 1971 war with Pakistan. Its ethos is “Any task, any time, any where” and the BSF has given blood and sweat to execute its motto “Jeevan Paryant Kartavya”.
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bsfranks">Border Security Force</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bsfmartyrs">Border Security Force</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string name="rpf_history">The Railway Protection Force has its origin since 1882 when the Railway Companies then in existence appointed their own security for each Department.  This arrangement   was   found   to be fairly satisfactory till 1918. With an increase in traffic; there was a steep rise in the incidence of thefts of goods entrusted to Railways. This led to the Government of India to appoint a committee to enquire into causes thereof and suggest corrective measures.
        \n\nActing on the Committee’s recommendations, most of the Class I Railways reorganized their security as a separate unit under a superior officer.  But this too proved inadequate, and in the aftermath of the Second World War, losses due to thefts and claims on the Railways assumed huge size and needed serious attention.
        \n\nThe  Government  of  India,  therefore in year 1954,  instituted  a  special  enquiry  through  Director, Intelligence Bureau (Ministry of Home Affairs) who in his report,  forcefully brought out  the  necessity  of  organizing  the  security in railways  on  a statutory basis.  The Railway Board  also  appointed  a  Security  Adviser  to the Railway Board in July, 1953 to work out the  details  for  the  reorganization  of  the  Security department.  It was decided in consultation  with  the  Ministry  of  Home  Affairs  that  there  should be an integrated well organized force on the model of the Police with adequate supervisory staff specially trained to  meet  the  peculiar  aspects of crime that were  prevalent  in  Railways  and  act  as  a  second  line  to  the  States  Police  with  whom,  under  the Constitution,  policing  on  Railways was rested.  This led to introduction of the R.P.F.  Bill in the Parliament of India for the better protection and security of Railway property and the same was passed as The Railway Protection Force Act, 1957 (No.23 of 1957).
        \n\nGradually and steadily the force has evolved in many aspects from then onwards and there after The RPF Act, 1957 was modified by Parliament for the first time in 1985 vide Act No.60 for the constitution and maintenance of the Force as an Armed Force of the Union and for the second time  in 2003 with Railway Act vide which the additional responsibilities of Passenger Safety and Security of their belongings were laid on the shoulder of the Force by extending the powers of execution of 29 sections of Railway Act. At present the Force is escorting maximum number of mail/express trains throughout the length and breadth of the nation beside the access control duties at important stations.\n\n</string>
    <string name="spg_history">Before 1981, the security of the Prime Minister of India at the Prime Minister\'s residence was the responsibility of the Special Security District of the Delhi Police under the charge of Deputy Commissioner of Police (DCP). In October 1981, a Special Task Force (STF) was raised by the Intelligence Bureau (IB) to provide ring-round and escort to the Prime Minister in and out of New Delhi.
        \n\nAfter the assassination of Prime Minister Indira Gandhi in October 1984, a review was undertaken by a Committee of Secretaries and it was decided to entrust security of the Prime Minister to a Special Group under unitary and direct control of a designated Officer and the STF to provide immediate security cover both in New Delhi and outside. These decisions were taken as short-term measures.
        \n\nThen on 18 February 1985, the Ministry of Home Affairs set up the Birbal Nath Committee to go into the issue in its entirety and submit its recommendation. In March 1985, the Birbal Nath Committee submitted its recommendations of raising a Special Protection Unit (SPU). On 30 March 1985, the President of India created 819 posts for the unit under the Cabinet Secretariat. The SPU was then re-christened Special Protection Group and the post of Inspector General of Police was re-designated as Director.
        \n\nThe SPG came into being on 8 April 1985 when S. Subramaniam, then Joint Director (VIP Security) in the Intelligence Bureau assumed office. Creation of the SPG required an elaborate exercise in order to clearly delineate responsibility of various agencies concerned with the security of the Prime Minister. The provisions contained in the Blue Book, which lays down security guidelines for the protection of the Prime Minister, had to be harmoniously blended with this new concept of proximate security.
        \n\nIB and the State/UT Police concerned were responsible for coordination, collection and dissemination of intelligence affecting VIP security. State/UT Police and the SPG were responsible for providing physical security arrangements for the Prime Minister, while the IB was to provide the required intelligence inputs to these operational agencies. The SPG functioned as a security group purely on the strength of an Executive Order for three years without a legislation, from April 1985 to June 1988.
        \n\nThe SPG was constituted and trained specially to provide protection to Prime Minister Rajiv Gandhi, in view of the threats to him from several sources. But, the organization created for the proximate security of Prime Minister Gandhi, did not contemplate provision of protection to him when he ceased to be Prime Minister, and faced magnified threats. SPG cover for Rajiv Gandhi was withdrawn once he ceased to be Prime Minister. After the assassination of Rajiv Gandhi in May 1991, the SPG Act was amended in 1991 to provide security to former Prime Ministers and their immediate families for a period of 10 years from the date on which the former Prime Minister ceased to hold office.\n\n</string>
    <string name="ndrf_history">The mid nineties and the subsequent decade saw much international debate and discussion around Disaster Response and Preparedness. Some of the notable and more impactful ones were the Yokohama Strategy Plan (1994) and the Hyogo Framework for Action (2005), adopted by the UN. During the same period India faced some of its most severe natural calamities like Orissa Super Cyclone (1999), Gujarat Earthquake (2001) and Indian Ocean Tsunami (2004). This succession of events and the International environment brought to fore, the need of comprehensive disaster management plan. This led to the enactment of the Disaster Management Act on December 26th , 2005. The National Disaster Management Authority (NDMA) was constituted to lay down the policies, plans and guidelines for disaster management.
        \n\nThe Disaster Management Act has statutory provisions for constitution of National Disaster Response Force (NDRF) for the purpose of specialized response to natural and man-made disasters. Accordingly, in 2006 NDRF was constituted with 8 Battalions. At present, NDRF has a strength of 12 Battalions with each Battalion consisting of 1149 personnel. In the beginning, the personnel of NDRF were deployed for routine law and order duties also. In a meeting of the NDMA with the Prime Minister on October 25, 2007, the need of NDRF being made a dedicated force was highlighted and accepted. This led to the notification of NDRF Rules on February 14th , 2008, making NDRF a dedicated force for disaster response related duties, under the unified command of DG NDRF.
        \n\nThe practice of “proactive availability” of this Force to the States and that of “pre-positioning”, in a threatening disaster situations have immensely helped minimise damage, caused due to natural calamities in the country. The first major test of disaster for NDRF was Kosi Floods in 2008. NDRF resources were moved to Bihar immediately after the breach in Kosi barrage on 19th August 2008. The situation was handled by the NDRF on a war footing, by airlifting 153 high speed motorized boats with 780 flood rescue trained personnel drawn from three different Battalions and sent to the five flood affected districts with utmost promptitude. As a result, over 1,00,000 affected people were rescued during the initial stage itself. The prompt and timely response of NDRF was appreciated by the then Chief Minister of Bihar.
        \n\nSince its inception NDRF has continued to win hearts of millions of countrymen, by demonstrating its expertise and compassion while handling disaster situations. The list of such challenges is long. To cite a few ; a six storey building collapsed at Bellary (Karnataka) in January 2010. In a meticulously planned, round the clock operation lasting seven days, the NDRF rescued 20 trapped live victims and retrieved 29 bodies. In a multi-storey factory building collapse at Jalandhar (Punjab) in April 2012, the NDRF successfully rescued 12 live victims trapped under huge rubble of debris and also recovered 19 dead bodies. The sterling services rendered by 46 NDRF personnel in response to the triple disaster in Japan in March-April 2011, has also won NDRF laurels.
        \n\nIn September 2014, the Jammu and Kashmir region suffered disastrous floods across many of its districts caused by torrential rainfall. This was the first-ever experience for NDRF to handle urban flooding on such a massive scale. At the time that the NDRF teams arrived in Srinagar in response to the sudden floods, there was huge expanse of water, clusters of half-submerged houses, broken bridges, roads which were washed away and lakhs of people stranded on rooftops. Adding to the woes were non functional communication and electricity supply. NDRF, with an initial strength of 10 teams and 50 inflatable rubberized boats, was engaged relentlessly in evacuating stranded people and saving lives. Subsequently, the strength of teams was raised to 23 with more than 150 boats, which rescued more than 50,000 people and distributed nearly 80 tones of relief material.
        \n\nWhen cyclone Hud-hud pounded the eastern Indian coast in October 2014, NDRF personnel were present there to save lives of the affected people. They used saw cutters to cut big trees and other metal objects likely to be uprooted and scattered by the gusty and ferocious winds of Hud-hud.
        \n\nWhen on 25 April 2015, an earthquake with a magnitude of 7.8 and a depth of 15 km struck Nepal, India’s National Disaster Response Force made the headlines by capitalizing the golden hours’ rule of disaster management by being the first on the ground. In the rescue operations, the personnel of NDRF pulled out 11 live victims out of a total figure of 16.
        \n\nIn later part of 2015, NDRF created a milestone in one of the marathon rescue operations of its kind in Bilaspur tunnel accident in Himachal Pradesh when two workers were trapped for nine days. Two workers were safely retrieved from a collapsed under-construction tunnel. In month of Dec 2015 unprecedented rain has flooded parts of Tamilnadu and Puducherry which resulted in urban flood in Chennai and its suburbs. NDRF mobilised 50 USAR teams from different location across the country by Air and timely evacuated more than 14,000 flood affected people and shifted them to safer areas. NDRF teams also assisted local administration by providing immediate relief and medical care to thousands of needy people. Role of NDRF during Chennai was appreciated by all corners of society,
        \n\nBesides the professionalism shown during rescue operations in floods and cyclones and collapsed structure search and rescue (CSSR) operations, NDRF has also acquired considerable expertise in facing CBRN (Chemical, Biological, Radiological and Nuclear) challenges. . The creditable task of NDRF in retrieving Cobalt-60 radiological material at Mayapuri, Delhi, during April and May 2010 has been an acid test of NDRF's CBRN capability.
        \n\nToday NDRF is a distinguished, unique Force across the country functioning under the Ministry of Home Affairs, Government of India, within the overall command, control and leadership of the Director General, NDRF.</string>
    <string name="spg_mission">There are standard operating procedures laid down to protect the PM wherever he goes – be it domestic or foreign tour. This included everything from anti-sabotage checks, sanitizing of venues and personal security details.
\n\nThere are detailed operational procedures in place specifying everything like the number of men accompanying him in the car, at the dias, etc. They also keep a strict check on who meets PM and who is allowed to meet. The SPG also answers the PM’s phone calls and ask the PM to decide whether to meet the person or not.
\n\nThe SPG protects the PM by forming multiple security rings around him. The members of the innermost ring have the sole mission of getting the PM to safety in case of an attack. The SPG Counter Assault Team usually form the second level. They are tasked with providing covering firepower to allow enough time for PM to get to safety.
\n\nBesides the main assault team that you see here, they may also be supported by a third cordon which include NSG, IAF and local forces for perimeter and aerospace safety.\n\n</string>

    <string name="itbp_histroy">Indo-Tibetan Border Police was raised on October 24, 1962 for reorganizing the frontier intelligence and security set up along the Indo-Tibetan border. Only four Battalions were sanctioned to begin with. ITBP was initially raised under the CRPF Act. However, in 1992, parliament enacted the ITBPF Act and the rules there under were framed in 1994.\n

With additional tasks entrusted to ITBP from time to time on border guarding, counter insurgency and internal security roles, the number of ITBP Battalions increased gradually and ITBP presently has 56 service Battalions, 4 Specialist Battalions, 17 Training Centres and 07 logistics establishments with a total strength of approx. 90,000 personnel.\n

In the year 2004, in pursuance of GoM recommendations on “One Border One Force”, the entire stretch of India-China Border comprising 3488 Kms was assigned to the ITBP for Border Guarding duty and, accordingly, ITBP, replaced Assam Rifles in Sikkim and Arunachal Pradesh in 2004.\n

The motto of the Force is “Shaurya-Dridhata-Karma Nishtha” (Valour – Determination – Devotion to Duty). All ranks of ITBP are dedicated to guard the borders with valour, determination and devotion to duty. The Force has earned number of decorations like Padmashree-7, Kirti Chakra-2 Shaurya Chakra-6, Sena Medal-1, President’s Police Medal for Gallantry-19, Police Medal for Gallantry -91, Parakram Padak-79, President’s Police and Fire Service Medals for Gallantry-2, Prime Minister’s Life Saving Medal-86, Jeewan Raksha Padak -06, Sarvottam Jeewan Raksha Padak – 02, Uttam Jeewan Raksha Padak – 13, Tenzing Norgay Adventure Award -12 etc. for its numerous achievements in the past.</string>

    <string name="ssb_history">In the wake of the Chinese conflict in 1962, it was felt that the borders of the country could not be protected with the force of rifles alone. It required the backing and resolute will of a committed border population. In addition, it needed an in-depth understanding and familiarity of the terrain as well as the culture and ethos of the border population. A  need was, therefore,  realized for the creation of a unique, unconventional yet specialized organization, which would function in the far, flung, vulnerable, strategic, remote, climatically and topographically difficult border areas and motivate the border population across several states towards the cause of protecting our national sovereignty.\n\n\n

    The Special Service Bureau (now Sashastra Seema Bal) was thus conceived in November 1962 and eventually created in March 1963 with the sole objective of achieving ‘Total security preparedness’ in the remote border areas for performing a ‘stay-behind’ role in the event of a war. SSB was started in North Assam, North Bengal, hill districts of Uttar Pradesh (now Uttarakhand), Himachal Pradesh, part of Punjab and Ladakh area of JK. Shri B N Mullik took over as the first founder Director of Special Service Bureau and led the force from the front as the initial years were fraught with apprehensions on the prospects of another Chinese attack. The magnitude of responsibilities was such that each officer had to be constantly reassured of the value of his work in his own area of responsibility, so as to retain the motivation to continue to work towards the national objective, undeterred by the resistance encountered and the invisibility of the impact of the hard work put in. However, the appropriate support and cooperation came from the successive PMs, Dy PMs, Governors, CMs, etc., which bolstered the endeavour and morale of the SSB officers and staff, immensely.\n\n\n

        Later, the jurisdiction of SSB was extended to Manipur, Tripura and Jammu (1965), Meghalaya (1975), Sikkim (1976), Rajasthan (1985), South Bengal, Nagaland and Mizoram (1989). Its area of coverage included 15 states. SSB in the erstwhile role was covering a population of more than 5.73 crores living in about 80,000 villages and about 9917 Kms of India’s international borders.\n
        The area covered by SSB was distributed into 10 SSB Divisions, each headed by a Divisional Commissioner, 49 Areas headed by Area Organisers, 117 Sub Areas headed by Sub Area Organisers and 287 Circles headed by Circle Organisers. These units were key centres, coordinating and supervising all activities to fulfill their respective obligations. It also had 25 battalions of combatised personnel that provided arms training to volunteers who formed the core of the armed village resistance, in case of another war. These personnel were spread out across 32 Group Centres, 14 Training Centres and 3 Storage Depots. Training Schools were set up in various parts of the country starting with Frontier Administrative Officers’ Training Centre at Mahabaleshwar in October, 1963. Besides this, one Group Leaders Training School was opened in Gwaldam (then a part of Uttar Pradesh, now Uttarakhand).Two Advanced Training Schools were started for volunteers in Sarahan (HP) and Haflong (Assam). A High Altitude Training Centre was set up in Didihat, which was later shifted to Frontier Academy Gwaldam where a dedicated Mountaineering wing still conducts various rock climbing, snow survival and mountaineering courses. By 1990, SSB had seven Major Training Centres and seven Women’s Advanced Training Schools. Training was imparted to the population in the border areas of HP, Punjab, part of JK, UP, North Assam, North Bengal and South Bengal and NEFA region.\n\n\n
        Since 1963, the main thrust of the SSB was on generating a sense of national belonging, security and vigilance. Village Level Training Programmes and Refresher Training Courses in civil defence were started to train villagers to defend their own villages and if the situation demanded, to participate in a ‘stay behind role’ for the nation. Villagers were trained in the use of small arms and the art of self defence to develop a spirit of resistance. In early 1970s we also started National Integration Programmes in a big way. All these bore fruit slowly but surely. However, the rifle training was a big draw and brought lakh of people into our fold. The trained volunteers became the eyes and ears of SSB, on the border and could be drawn on whenever required. As a result the number of Chinese intelligencers prodding our border reduced considerably.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_bsfabout">Border Security Force</string>
    <string name="title_activity_itbpabout">Indo-Tibetan Border Police</string>
    <string name="title_activity_itbphistory">Indo-Tibetan Border Police</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ssbabout">Sashastra Seema Bal</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ssbhistory">Sashastra Seema Bal</string>
</resources>
