<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Module4</string>
    <string name="nsg_mission">The National Security Guard (NSG) is an Indian special forces unit under the Ministry of Home Affairs (MHA). It was raised in 1984, following Operation Blue Star and the assassination of Indira Gandhi (for combating terrorist activities with a view to protect states against internal disturbances).
        \n\nNSG is under the authority of Ministry of Home Affairs. However it is not categorised under the uniform nomenclature of Central Armed Police Forces. It has a special forces mandate, and its core operational capability is provided by the Special Action Group (SAG) which is drawn from the Indian Army. The Special Rangers Group (SRG), the police component of NSG, which also handles VIP security, is composed of personnel on deputation from other Central Armed Police Forces and State Police Forces.
\n\nThe NSG personnel are often referred to in the media as Black Cats because of the black outfit and black cat insignia worn on their uniform.
\n\nThe National Security Guard (NSG) was set up in 1984 as a Federal Contingency Deployment Force to tackle all facets of terrorism in the country. As a specialized counter terrorism force, it is intended for use (only in exceptional situations) and not meant to take over the (functions of the State Police Forces or other Para Military Forces). Yet, over the years its role has vastly expanded to provide personal security to influential politicians quite independent of the real threat that they face.
\n\nThe NSG is trained to conduct counter terrorist task to including counter hijacking tasks on land, sea, and air; Bomb disposal (search, detection and neutralization of IEDs); PBI (Post Blast Investigation) and Hostage Rescue missions.
    </string>
    <string name="nsg_sel">Selection is demanding and has a drop out rate of about 70–80 percent. Three of their 14 months of training in Manesar, Haryana, are devoted to the basics.The basic training period lasts 90 days. Physical fitness training has 26 elements, ranging from a cross-country obstacle course to jumping from heights and across divides and scaling different kinds terrain. One endurance test involves martial arts, target shooting at the end of an obstacle-ridden cross-country run. This is meant to gauge the candidate’s performance under conditions of stress and exhaustion. Those who successfully complete the tests are sent for nine months of advanced training.</string>
    <string name="nsg_reg_dep">In response to criticism of the time taken by NSG units to arrive in November 2008 Mumbai attacks, from their base in Manesar, Haryana, the MHA decided to deploy NSG contingents in major cities across India like Mumbai, Kolkata (462 personnel), Hyderabad and Chennai.
    \n\nHyderabad will also serve as a regional center in the future. With the ministry of home affairs (MHA) giving its nod and sanctioning Rs 533.68 crore a few months ago, the National Security Guard (NSG) officials are gearing up to set up the Southern Regional Center (SRC) at Ibrahimpatnam, Hyderabad for training commandos. With the state government also handing over 600 acres at Ibrahimpatnam, the SRC is likely to be ready by next year. Tender notices have already been issued for civil works, which would be overseen by the Central Public Works Department. With this, Hyderabad would have an NSG hub at Trimulgherry as well as the SRC for training "Black Cats". As of now, nearly 300 commandos, ready for anti-terror operations round-the-clock, are stationed at the NSG hub at Trimulgherry. Similar hubs are in place in Mumbai, Chennai and Kolkata. The proposal to set up a state-of-the-art NSG training centre at Ibrahimpatnam on the lines of NSG Manesar training centre has been pending for over three years.
        \n\nBut the MHA officials, in their annual report released recently, announced the release of funds for developing infrastructure. "Post the 26/11 Mumbai terror strike, four regional hubs of NSG were operationalised in Mumbai, Hyderabad, Chennai and Kolkata to reduce reaction time. A regional centre at Hyderabad is also being raised, for which 600 acres of land has been acquired. MHA has conveyed sanction of Rs 533.68 crore towards the construction of this Southern Regional Centre, NSG at Ibrahimpatnam," the MHA report said. With this, the state would have two trained anti-terror striking forces. Besides the NSG, the Andhra Pradesh police's OCTOPUS, which also has a training facility at Ibrahimpatnam, has a strength of over 250 personnel. NSG and OCTOPUS personnel, who undergo a gruelling training, including handling sophisticated weapons, commandos are sent back to their parent department once they attain the age of 35, ensuring that the force remains young and fighting fit.
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_bsfmission">Border Security Force</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        Till 1965 India’s borders with Pakistan were manned by the
        State Armed Police Battalion. Pakistan attacked Sardar Post,
        Chhar Bet and Beria Bet on 9 April, 1965 in Kutch. This exposed
        the inadequacy of the State Armed Police to cope with armed
        aggression due to which the Government of India felt the
        need for a specialized centrally controlled Border Security
        Force, which would be armed and trained to man the International
        Border with Pakistan. As a result of the recommendations of the
        Committee of Secretaries, the Border Security Force came into
        existence on 01 Dec 1965, and Shri K F Rustamji was the first
        chief and founding father. Shri K K Sharma, IPS is current Director
        General of the BSF.\n\n\n

        The BSF, in its 53rd years of existence, has emerged as an elite force of the country having excelled with distinction in the 1971 war with Pakistan. Its ethos is “Any task, any time, any where” and the BSF has given blood and sweat to execute its motto “Jeevan Paryant Kartavya”.
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bsfranks">Border Security Force</string>
</resources>
